# Santiago Cuervo Rojas

Reservoir Engineer

Carrera 3 # 21-46 Apto 1703A Bogotá, Colombia (+57-301) 738 8439

Phone: (+57) 241 0992 | Mobile: (+57-301) 738 8439 scuervo91@gmail.com

# **PERFIL**

M.Eng. in Petroleum Engineering with +4 years of experience on integrated Reservoir Engineering, focused on the realization of optimal development plans of primary and secondary Oil & Gas reserves, applying transversal knowledge of geoscience, reservoir-well-surface, economic and risk. Great interest in the development of work tools through numerical programming languages (Spreadsheets, Octave and Julia). Knowledge in reservoir simulation for enhanced oil recovery applications such as water and steam injection. Comprehensive experience Reservoir-well-surface models nodal analysis and performance evaluation of artificial lift systems (ESP, UBH, PCP, UBM). Petrophysical characterization and quantification of reserves by volumetric methods, declination curves and material balance. Evaluation of exploration prospects with geological knowledge. Knowledge in the implementation of artificial intelligence algorithms. Able to build dynamic optimization models including deterministic and stochastic models for decision making and risk analysis. Good understanding of physical, mathematical and financial models for the economic evaluation of projects. Understanding the English foreign language and abilities to work in a multidisciplinary team.

Web Page Repositories: https://github.com/scuervo91

## **EXPERIENCE**

July 2016 – July 2019

Omega Energy Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia Integral Reservoir Engineer

Geosciences

- Interpretation of well logs
- Development tool visualization and analysis of well logs (Scheduled in Julia)
- Evaluation of Prospects (Volumetry and Risk)
- Development of Geostatistics tool for the settlement of properties
- Development Stochastic tool using Monte Carlo simulation for calculations of resources and reserves (programmed in Octave)

### Reservoir

- Evaluation of Reserves (Balance of Matter and Declination Curves) Interaction with Certifiers
- Development Forecast tool for the production of crude oil and / or gas reservoirs integrated into a model of material balance and nodal analysis (programmed in Octave)
- Reservoir Characterization Models (Fluid-Rock)
- Analytical models for the evaluation of incremental production models
- Interpretation of well pressure tests
- Definition of development plans (Primary and Secondary)
- Development of reservoir simulation models Black Oil 2 Phases (programmed in Octave)

#### **Production**

- Construction of Nodal Analysis for oil and gas wells for production optimization.
- Monitoring of parameters of artificial lifting methods (PCP, ESP, Jet Pump)
- Development Evaluation tool and performance of ESP system, UBH (Programmed in Octave)
- Basic design of lifting systems

# **Operations**

- Guard in the daily operations of production
- Strategies for process optimization

# Development Tools

- Development of Julia Language complementary packages for the Oil & Gas industry in the Geosciences, Reserves, Production, Economic and integrated areas. (Developing).
- Developed Packages
- WellLogs.jl 2 Visualization of Well Records and Petrophysical calculations https://github.com/scuervo91/WellLogs.jl
- WellProductivity .jl ? Productivity analysis, IPR Declination, VFP https://github.com/scuervo91/WellProductivity.jl
- Geomechanics.jl → Geomechanics Analysis focused on Unconventional Reservoirs

https://github.com/scuervo91/Geomechanics.jl

- WellTesting.jl → Well pressure Test (DrawDown & BuildUp)
   https://github.com/scuervo91/WellTesting.jl
- LinearSolvers.jl → Linear system of equations solvers to implement on Reservoir Simulation

https://github.com/scuervo91/LinearSolvers.jl

- MachineLearning.jl → Implementation of basic algorithms of machine learning

https://github.com/scuervo91/MachineLearning.jl

- Packages to Develop
- Reservoir Analysis MBE, Simulation, PVT, Pressure Testing
- - Economic Analysis Economic Evaluation
- Integration Machine Learning

# 2015 - 2016

# IKM Information Knowledge & Management, Bogotá, Colombia

Oilfield Data analyst -

Hocol Project: Sorting Oilfield data through metadata, and uploading into documental software to be easily available whenever is required.

# 2013-2014

#### **Hocol S.A.,** Bogotá-Colombia

#### Jr Reservoir Engineer Thesis:

Publication: "Technical evaluation of steam drive injection, cyclic steam injection and Steam-Assisted gravity Drainage in a field on Llanos basin through simulation": PVT Analysis; Adjustment of equations of state; simulation model Constructions; Uncertainty analysis; development plans using probabilistic methods; Financial Evaluation.

#### 2012 - 2013

# Indra Colombia, Bogotá, Colombia

**Junior Engineer**: PAI-OPENWELLS project. Analyze and register chronologically information about operational jobs made in the Ecopetrol wells, like work-overs and well-service ensuring the quality of the data. Transfer that information from the

corporative software to OpenWells

2010-2011 National Oilwell Varco de Colombia, Barrancabermeja, Colombia

Intership:

Tracing the solid waste treatment operations and water control for drilling muds in La

Cira Infantas Field.

## **EDUCATION**

July 2019 M. Eng. In Petroleum Engineering

Universidad de Los Andes, Bogotá- Colombia

2014 B. Eng in Petroleum Engineering

Universidad de América, Bogotá – Colombia

Curse - 2016 Reservoir Geomechanics

Standford University

# **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

Microsoft Office Advanced Excel, Word, PowerPoint

Oil Wells tools OpenWells, Profile, Data Analizer

Nodal Analysis Prosper – Gap -Mbal Basic

**Reservoir Simulation** IMEX – STARS – WINPROP - CMOST

PVT Simulators WINPROP-PVTSIM-KAPPA PVT

**Probabilistic Simulators** Crystal Ball – @Risk

**Decision Making** Expert Choice – HiView – DPL – Crystal

Ball - Hugin

**Optimization** Excel Solver – OpenSolver – Linear

Programming Xpress – Non Linear Programming Gams – Crystal Ball

Math MatLab - Octave

Seismic Petrel - Opendtec

# **LANGUAGE**

- Spanish primary language for speaking, writing, reading
- English secondary language for speaking, writing, reading B1

# **MEMBER**

• SPE COLOMBIA – SOCIETY OF PETROLEUM ENGINEERS

# **DEVELOPMENT INTEREST**

• Development of OIL & GAS Tools in Programming Language: Geosciences, Deposits, Production, Economic Evaluation, Machine Learning, Integrated Models

# **REFERENCES**

**Fernando Pérez**Senior Reservoir Engineer
+57 3102315812

Julian Rojas CEO Savia Perú +51 953923 608